How do I sound?
>> You sound perfect.
>> You sound great.
>> I look? Yeah, you sound great. Better
than you look.
You got that face made for radio.
You [laughter] don't look as tired as
you have in recent weeks. That's true.
Yeah. Yeah.
>> Somebody was slagging me for the bags
under my eyes. I mean, this audience is
brutal. [music] They're brutal. They're
brutal. It's a good thing I'm rich.
>> [laughter]
[music]
>> You let your winners ride.
Rain Man David Sacks
>> [music]
>> And I said, we open sourced it to the
fans and they've just gone crazy [music]
with it. Love you, Sacksy.
All right, everybody. Welcome back to
the number one podcast in the world.
It's the All-In podcast. With us today,
Chamath Palihapitiya, David Sacks, and
our fifth bestie, Mr. Brad Gerstner is
here. I think David Friedberg is
suffering from some
socialist-related flu. He's very sick of
reading about socialists, but he'll be
back next week with two incredible,
incredible interviews. You guys see
those Spencer Pratt ads? Wow.
>> It's one of the best political ads I've
ever ever seen. Oh, there's like three
or four of them.
>> There are multiples. Yeah.
>> Whoever that social media team is is on
fire. If you get a good social media
team and you get a good ad production
team, I think it's next gen cuz these
things go crazy. And Spencer Pratt, if
he wins this election, which I think
he's going to in Los Angeles, the reason
is what Brad said. Those ads are
incredible. Well, he's also quite a good
debater. Did you see clips from this
debate? Incredible. He's so funny. He's
so chill. Yeah, well, he's up against
Karen Bass, who's the mayor, who is
basically extremely left-wing. And then
there's someone who's a city
councilwoman, who's even further to the
left of Karen Bass. I mean, she's Yeah,
yeah.
>> often like Fidel Castro territory. She's
an Indian Fidel Castro. Raman. So, she
was basically, I guess, criticizing the
mayor for the homelessness problem.
And then Pratt pointed out that this
councilwoman is actually in charge of
all these homeless programs already.
>> [laughter]
>> He eviscerated her. He eviscerated her.
And he basically made the key point,
which is, "Look, the problem here is not
lack of housing, it's an addiction
issue, and it's a mental illness issue."
And he said, "Look, if you
>> he said
he said if she went to the street, she'd
get stabbed in the neck. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Which is pretty accurate if you've been
to Skid Row. I mean, you would not want
to walk through there.
It was like the Spider-Man photo.
>> got the clip. Play the clip, Nick. Oh,
god. This clip is brutal.
>> a different clip, but this one super
viral. It reminded me of Trump a little
bit. Let's see. I'm not sure how to
respond to that vision of Los Angeles.
This is a MAGA Republican's idea
of what Los Angeles looks like. This is
This is really not
>> [laughter]
>> Unbelievable.
For those of you listening, he put his
hands up and wiggled his head like, "Oh
my god."
>> [laughter]
>> Hey, hey, Sax. You know, Stephen Pratt
wins mayor, Spencer Pratt. And then
Spencer the you know, the ballot
initiative, the retirement protection
and savings act, right? It's going to
pass going to pass with big numbers.
This is the, you know, referendum that
effectively is going to knock out the
wealth tax. Can you imagine if
California effectively passes a
constitutional amendment protecting
retirement savings and personal assets
and banning the wealth tax and Pratt
gets elected, the message that would
send to the country? That's That's a
very non-consensus view that I'm
becoming increasingly optimistic about.
Well, from your lips to God's ears.
But until that message actually is sent,
I think I'm going to be uh in Texas. In
Texas.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, I mean, this is also in the face
of I don't know, just a follow-up story
here, but Mondami did like an attack
video on Ken Griffin's house. We talked
about it on the pod a couple weeks ago.
And like literally stood in front of his
house, pointed at it. and this is in the
face of like a CEO getting shot for
ideological reasons, Sam Altman's house
being targeted. This is like a really
dangerous thing for Mondami to do.
And Ken Griffin came out today in or
yesterday in an interview and said,
"Hey, listen, I'm out. We're going to be
putting our efforts into
Florida." And this is the same thing
that happened to Chicago, and he
basically said like I really felt
offended and I was, you know, nervous
about this
because of my personal safety. And he
called him out. Mondami came out with
like a a mealy-mouthed response that
didn't even apologize for what he did.
Just double down on it essentially. All
right, let's get to the I don't know if
you guys saw it or not, but who cares?
And New York is becoming a flyover city.
It's an interesting way to put it. Don't
disagree. All right, first story. Elon
just leased all of Colossus 1. His data
center? He did?
Nostro What? What?
Yes, shocking to Dario and Anthropic.
Chamath on this week's pod. Go ahead and
give yourself a pat on the back. You
said Elon and Dario should do a deal
tomorrow. It didn't happen. The next day
it happened 5 days later, so you came
close, Chamath. But no cigar because of
Anthropic's obvious compute constraints.
Anthropic just added over 220,000 Nvidia
GPUs, over 300 megawatts of energy.
The deal is already having an impact as
we've discussed here. Claude users have
been experiencing rate limits. Well,
Claude has now doubled the Claude code
rate limits, removed peak usage caps for
paid users, and increased API volumes
for Opus models. XAI is now trading
their models at Colossus 2. So, they
have more than enough compute. Elon made
a great bet
on compute and built up those data
centers really fast, and that is now
paying off. We had the cursor deal we
talked about last week. Let's talk about
the emergence of Elon Web Services, EWS,
Chamath. He is now in the hyperscaler
competing against Google Cloud, Amazon
Web Services, and Azure. And uh I don't
know if you had inside information or
just a brilliant uh epiphany, but uh
take us behind the call and what do you
think about the deal itself?
I think the deal is fantastic. I'll say
maybe three quick things.
The first is, as I mentioned a couple
weeks ago,
Anthropic
and OpenAI's revenue performance has
nothing to do with demand. Zero.
It is entirely to do with the supply
constraints that exist in data centers
and specifically in power.
If they had infinite power, I think that
their revenues would probably be even
more parabolic.
And so all the breathlessness about
either exceeding or underperforming a
forecast, in my opinion, mean nothing.
I think the five-year view
for those two companies
is quite robust.
The thing that they really need is more
compute and more power. That's the first
thing.
The second thing is, while they need
that, we have a very big problem,
which is we unfortunately have very poor
leadership
at the head
of most of these AI firms.
I think they are coming off as
untrustworthy or too self-interested.
The political reaction now
is starting to turn negative.
The community reaction is negative.
You have about nine gigawatts that are
supposed to come online this year.
Almost 50% of it now is being protested.
More than likely, if if history holds,
most of that will get turned off. So
they will get even more supply
constrained. So that's the setup.
So what's the opportunity? I think for
Elon, if you look inside of how people
try to nitpick the SpaceX valuation
case, or let's not even Let's give them
Sorry, let's be more generous.
When people try to paint the bear case,
or they try to red team the valuation,
the biggest element is the on the come
value around the orbital data centers.
And by actually landing a bunch of
terrestrial capacity,
I think you start to blunt that. Because
you can now start to say that even if
the orbital data centers get delayed by
a few months or a few quarters, even if
the technological
de-risking of it takes longer,
he now has a structural core business
that will effectively subsidize
his ability to train Grok, which I think
is a really important and underreported
theme.
So, you have all this infrastructure.
He somehow saw the tea leaves
before most people. He built to a level
of scale and secured power
before most people. It is now become the
critical asset. Now, he's
kind of king-making.
And I think that that's a really
interesting valuation
reinforcement as SpaceX goes through
testing the waters in the in the
roadshow. Brad, your take.
Yeah, no, I think it's well said. I
mean, first we we know that there's
nobody better on planet Earth than Elon
at converting electrons to tokens. It's
a critically important evolution to the
story. You know, I think our friend
Shawn Maguire, he he he sent out a tweet
that summed it up well, and he said
SpaceX has this five-layer cake: launch,
connectivity, compute, hyperscaler,
space data centers, and then
applications and models, and then other
bets, right? The question on the
roadshow has been, "But x.ai doesn't on
the revenue trajectory of OpenAI and and
Anthropic, and yet there are huge
commitments. And now we see the ace card
that Elon's playing." He said he was
building AWS all along or EWS all along.
And so I estimate that this is going to
generate in this year an incremental 45
billion dollars of revenue on top of
what I have seen analyst estimates in
the mid-20s. That's a material amount of
incremental revenue to offset the cost
of the investments that he's made here.
And that will subsidize to Chamath's
point all that he's investing to build
the next generation of Grok. Remember
too that he has three facilities,
Colossus, Macro Hard and Macro Harder,
1.2 gigawatts in Macro Hard and Macro
Harder in Blackwell. So he's given the
one that's kind of less connected,
H100s, great for inference to Anthropic.
He's monetizing it in a big way. It's
terrific for Anthropic. And it solves
what I think was the biggest question in
the valuation story, which is what if he
spends ahead of x.ai's revenue. It takes
the pressure, Chamath, off x.ai
delivering immediate revenue. Now he
becomes
uh an immediate competitor in the
hyperscale. I don't think this is the
last announcement. I think he's going to
make a lot more,
you know, moves in this direction. I
think it will be a material part of
their story and their revenue
projections
uh as they come together. And I would
just say finally, you know, again,
everybody has talked about how we don't
have enough power, how we don't have
enough compute, how the revenues would
not show up in this year. You know, but
the chaos that is American capitalism
somehow finds a way, okay? And there's
tremendous demand for Anthropic, and we
find a way. I was so happy to see kind
of the detente and the kind exchange
between the team at Anthropic and Elon
because we need all of this in order to
produce uh American frontier models to
stay at the frontier.
And then finally, I just say, you know,
Chamath, you referenced these activists
that are protesting delaying these data
centers
in in these localities. One thing I want
to dispel this myth. These This is not
like organic hyper local protests by
people in a community that aren't being
spurred on.
This is highly organized activists that
are moving across the country to stir up
trouble in the exact same way they did
to stop all fission reactors being built
30 years ago in America. Now we have no
nuclear reactors being built. China's
got a hundred of them. Who was funding
those activists? I think we need to
really look into who's funding the
activists now. I'm not saying that there
aren't any concerns, but the
misinformation about water, the
misinformation about electricity bills
electricity bills are going up in the
places that are not building data
centers. New York and California because
they haven't built any supply on the
grid. In Texas, where you're building
the most data centers in the country,
electricity costs are going down. So, um
I'm I I I think that's a boogeyman that
we got to take on.
Sacks, sure that's
Well, look, the deal is highly
complimentary as Chamath and Brad
pointed out. SpaceX has a profitable, I
think very profitable,
space and telecommunications Starlink
business, the satellite business, but
the xAI business had huge losses. The
reason's pretty straightforward. You
need these super large training
clusters, but they cost a lot of money.
And until you have a model that's
capable of competing at the frontier,
you're not making any revenue. And that
problem was compounded by the fact that
right now all the revenue is in
enterprise, which is to say coding. We
know that xAI just did that deal with
Cursor to try and catch up, but they
don't have a coding product yet. So,
they're not participating in the
revenue, but they're participating in
all of the cost. So, this deal fixes
that problem.
Elon's now able to have a frontier model
company, but he's able to now not have
these massive unpaid for CapEx
commitments, right? Because he's able to
kind of lease that capacity. So, I think
it solves a major problem for them and
their balance sheet. And then you have
to say that for Anthropic, this is a
really great thing because they were
compute constrained.
And just to build on that point, I mean,
I guess let me be the first to
congratulate Dario on winning the AI
race.
And you've been Let's be honest, Sachs,
you have been
on this podcast, you've been moderately
critical of that company and Dario
himself for being um, you know, a little
P-doomer 110. And on your X account,
you've been even a little spicier. So,
now that there's peace in the Middle
East of
of the AI business, what's your take
here? My take is, look, let's just
honestly and accurately assess where the
state of this AI market is at right now
and Anthropic's place within it. So, for
the last 3 years, Anthropic has been
growing at a rate of 10x a year.
I think going into this year,
probably the conventional wisdom was
that there'd be no way to sustain that
kind of rate of growth at this level of
scale. And what happened in the first 4
months of the year? First, we find out
that from January 1st to March 31st,
they grew from roughly 10 billion of ARR
to 30 billion. So, it tripled. And then
in April, if anything, the rate of
increase seemed to accelerate. They went
from 30 to 44 billion of ARR. Nobody in
Silicon Valley has ever seen anything
like it. Forget about the rest of the
country. I mean, all we do in Silicon
Valley is deal with exponentials, and
still people have never seen that kind
of growth at that level of scale.
The only thing holding them back in the
future was compute. Now they've made
this deal. They've made other deals as
well to get that compute. I think it's
pretty much a foregone conclusion that
they will hit that forecast of 10x this
year, exiting the year at call it
roughly 100 billion of ARR. And now the
only question is whether they hit a
trillion
in 2027.
And we can debate whether that's
>> on board. No, we can't we can debate
whether that's true or not. But look, if
they do that,
I think they'll easily be the most
valuable tech company in history. In
fact, they might even be more valuable
than the rest of the Mag 7 put together.
Just to give people some basis for
comparison here. You know, the biggest
tech companies Apple, Nvidia, Nvidia,
Google. I think they they kind of do
around 4 to 500 billion a year right now
of of revenue. I mean, I guess Nvidia's
a little bit of a different category,
but you look at you look at Google.
>> the three hyperscalers. Yeah. I mean,
Google is doing what? Like 120 billion a
quarter? Something like that. 100
billion a quarter. Correct. But growing
at what? 20% year over year? Not 100%
and certainly not 1,000%.
So, the fact that Anthropic could be on
track, in fact, let me correct that.
>> them going to the Mag 8? It'll be a Mag
8. I'm saying something else, which is
that
unless something about their current
trajectory
changes,
Anthropic will be the most powerful
monopoly ever created in human history.
Oh.
Again, it will be, you know, a trillion
dollars of ARR growing at some
exponential Interesting.
>> Dario calls it AGI. I call it the
biggest monopoly in human history.
Interesting to hear that word monopoly,
Sacks. Very interesting placement.
Chamath, go ahead and then we'll move.
>> Apple in 2025 was 420 billion.
Microsoft was 300 billion. Alphabet was
390 billion. Amazon 700 billion. Nvidia
190 billion. Meta 185 billion. Tesla 110
billion. Total
about 2.3 to 2.35 trillion. So, if Sacks
is right,
and Anthropic,
you know, can tack on a trillion, it
won't be the Mag 7, it'll be the Mag 1.
Just to put it in perspective though,
Dario and Dwarkesh said he thought the
combined AI revenue
of the market leaders would be about a
trillion in 2029. I love what you're
saying, Zach's. I think there is
unlimited TAM. We may be over our skis a
little bit in terms of, you know, the
forecast. If you back your way from
compute, right? They're They expect to
have 5 gigs by the end of this year, 10
gigs by the end of next year. It's kind
of hard to get to those numbers for a
single company, but I do believe that
the, you know, trajectory that they're
on, I totally agree with you, is on an
exponential that not many people
believed in 4 months ago. Right. So,
then the question is, okay, I think we
all agree they're on an exponential
curve and that the TAM is big enough to
support that. Just one data point on
TAM. My understanding of the total
market size just on coding
is 1 trillion, meaning that a trillion
dollars a year, roughly, is spent on
software developers and all things
related to the creation of software.
Now, I'm not saying that they eat that
entire market, but I can easily see the
market for software doubling.
>> Well, hold on. doubling from a trillion
to 2 trillion, given that
coding tokens basically 10 X's or 100
X's the value of that market and the
ability to generate code. So, I think we
all agree that the TAM here is large
enough to support a trillion dollars of
revenue. Brad, I think you bring up a
couple of really important constraints.
First, there may not be enough compute
and there's not enough energy. I'd say
the second big one is, what's the
competitive reaction going to be?
Totally. Because I would say at the
beginning of this year, all these
frontier labs were playing around with a
lot of different things. I mean,
Anthropic was the porcupine. They
believed in one thing. All these other
companies were kind of acting like the
fox who thinks they're good at a lot of
different things. They were doing nano
banana, they were doing Sora, they were
doing, you know, they were doing image
generation, they were doing fantasy
character chatbots. In hindsight, they
were doing a lot of things that appeared
to be kind of a waste of time. The whole
market appears now to be coding and the
things that we built on coding tokens
like co-work, like agents. And so there
is going to be a competitive response
here where all the other guys realize,
"Oh, wait a second. We were misfocused."
They're going to get focused. I just
don't know how much share they're going
to be able to take. It does look like
OpenAI has already made the pivot. We
hear very good things about Codex now
based on GPT 5.5. 5.5 is based on a new
base model called Spud. I think they're
very optimistic about continuing
improvements. Their rate of growth
appears to be accelerating now because
of 5.5.
So, look, there's reason to believe that
OpenAI can take some share here. I'm
sure that Google won't be asleep at the
wheel. They're very, very good at
coding. They've got a really good team.
And Elon just tied up with Cursor. So,
there is going to be more competition.
But still, what you have to say,
and I think all of us know this from
Silicon Valley, is you always want to be
the company in the lead that's on that
trajectory where all you have to do is
maintain inertia, whereas the other
people have to change something in order
to put themselves back in the race. So,
this is when when I say somewhat sort of
facetiously, "Congratulations, Dario, on
winning the AI race." I don't mean that
he's won it, but he is winning it right
now. Well, here's the the brilliance of
what Elon's doing. If you look at the
existing business, which is Starlink and
basically the launch services at SpaceX,
incredible business, obviously.
20 billion this year, I think is the
estimate. But if you look at the
footprint of Amazon Web Services, Azure,
and GCP, you're looking at, you know,
300 billion dollars in revenue
and a market cap of combined 5 trillion,
4 trillion if these were independent
companies. And if you look at what is
Elon's core competency at Tesla, it's
building factories. And if you look at
the footprint of these factories,
they're huge. What are data centers?
They're basically big giant factories.
And then if you look at energy, what
else is Elon extremely good at? This is
the battery deployment and he's also got
solar deployment from the SolarCity
often criticized acquisition he did
years ago. So you put this all together,
if this is 5 billion as I think you
referenced Brad, if it's $5 billion in
incremental
Elon web services business and he's a
neo cloud, what could he build on planet
Earth, what could he build inside of
Tesla's in terms of extra compute, what
could he build inside the power wall?
What if the power walls had his new fabs
in them and you built a distributed
system from home to home? The power wall
has compute in it, the cars have compute
in it and of course
the ultimate manifestation of this where
nobody can complain is you go right out
into space. And that's what he's going
to do and the the sneaky small part of
this announcement from Elon and from
Anthropic and Dario was they're also
interested in space. So look for the
race to go from factories and data
centers to homes, the power wall with
compute in it. It's already online,
right? And Starlink also gives him the
ability to do distributed compute to
people's homes. Again, you could be
paying people to put power walls with
computer in it. That's going to be the
next shoe to drop, I believe. Did you
guys see the deal that was announced
yesterday
between Pulte Homes, which is a huge
builder,
>> Yes. They're doing it as well.
>> and Span? Yes. Nick, just throw this up
here. It's super cool. What's happening
is that these guys
are putting
many data centers with Nvidia GPU
clusters
beside every home and then allowing
people to actually run those things and
that's just incredible. I thought that
was so cool. It's a great pivot. What
this company did originally Chamath was
they did the power panel. They made
smart power panels. So you know when you
flip your breakers, all those breakers
are in an app. I looked at it for my
house, but I guess they pivoted to add
this and I think Base Power Brad urine
industrial unit they're going to do the
same thing.
>> Yep, Zach Dell's doing that. One of the
things I just would say in response,
Jason, to what you just said about Elon,
right? This is why the SpaceX IPO is
going to trade at 40 to 50 times
revenue, okay? So, next year, if they do
40 to 50 billion, and this thing goes
out at 2 trillion, right? That they're
going to trade at a really high revenue
multiple compared to the Mag 5 that are
trading at like 25 times earnings. And
there's only one person on the planet
who has a future pipeline of innovation
and the largest TAM in the world because
he's playing in all these different
spaces that can command that multiple,
and it's Elon, and it's deserved, and
it's great for the country.
>> same Teslas has that same Elon
variable in it as well, which is people
value his companies at I would say two
times market, three times market, four
times market because of the future
pipeline. You guys And they devalue
Apple because they don't have somebody
like Elon or Steve Jobs there who is
giving them the future.
>> I don't think it's devalued. I think Or
properly valued if you don't have an
Elon and you have somebody like I think
that's exactly what it is. We talked
about this last week, but explain why
you think it's different.
>> all of these companies are actually very
fairly valued, and then
Elon world gets a premium. Totally. And
that premium is because of what you guys
said. That I agree with. The big message
that I take away from this, which the
markets
and retail are telling you is
you guys have stopped innovating.
There's a lot of incrementalism,
and we as a society aren't benefiting
broadly the way that you told us we
would be.
And so, maybe this is the best way for
them to get this message, which is to
whack their valuation. And by the way,
I'll just say it again, when Tesla and
SpaceX merge and we have all things Elon
in Elon Corp, okay, which will happen
probably by at end of the year, maybe
it'll happen in the middle of next year.
It's going to then break everybody's
brains again because you'll have this
one asset, as you guys said, that will
trade at a valuation premium. And some
people will say it's unexplainable. And
I think it's logically explainable,
which is everybody else has stopped
innovating. People know how to draw more
blood from the stone, how to target
better ads.
That does nothing for society anymore.
>> Yeah, that's it. Literally In fact, it
does the opposite. It There is no good
left.
>> That was literally the exact point I was
making when you cut me off. If you look,
Tim Cook's greatest innovation
Tim Cook's greatest innovation, before
you cut me off, was Apple TV. Not even
the hardware product. It was just
spending money and making a Netflix
knockoff. There's been no other product
Hold on. Let me finish again before you
interrupt me making my point.
>> that? You don't like being interrupted?
Oh, no. Oh, yeah. Well, okay. Okay.
>> Go back to your interesting Pot, meet
kettle.
If you look at their track record, and I
think this is why we had a change there
is they have not done anything
innovative. And in fact, the things they
were doing that were innovating in AI or
self-driving cars, they shut down. They
won't take any swing for the bat. So,
they are getting penalized in their
valuation.
>> They're just not getting a premium.
They're not getting penalized.
>> I think they're getting penalized.
>> metric, they're trading at incredible
valuations. Just look at them. Oh, no. I
don't I I mean, if you compare the two
valuations, I think they're being
penalized. Anyway, let's Anybody else
want to get in on this before we move on
to the next one? Yeah. There is no world
in which Google and Meta and Apple and
Amazon could be viewed as being
penalized in valuation. There is very
clearly a world where Elon gets a
massive premium because he's innovating.
You're saying the same thing. You're
saying the same thing.
>> we're not the same thing. It's not the
same thing.
>> listen. We're I think we're we're
debating semantics here. I'm not letting
you off the hook, Saxby poo.
When Sax is very deliberate in how he
speaks, they said he's the captain of
the debate club in his 20,000 word
article this week and that he's a master
debater. He's a masturbator. And
you slipped in you slipped it in.
Are you saying that the FTC or whoever
should be going in and looking at
Anthropic? Oh, Brad's book is getting
attacked headwinds. You said they're a
monopoly or they're heading to monopoly
tactics Sacks is are that what you're
saying?
Well, look, I mean we know that tech
markets have a history of consolidating
down and turning into either monopolies
or duopolies. And if you just look at
the revenue right now, there's only two
companies making substantial revenue on
AI. It's Anthropic and Open AI. We know
that Open AI is growing at three to four
X, which is incredible at the level of
scale they're at. Anthropic though we
said is growing at an exponential 10X a
year. And if they just do that for 18
more months, they'll be by far the most
valuable company in human history and
they'll have unprecedented control over
the most important technology of our
time. So, I don't know what you call
that,
but it is something to think about. And
I guess I do have a thought experiment
for you guys,
which is
I just want you to think for a second
about the case of of John D.
Rockefeller, who I think is known as
probably
the most successful greatest monopolist
in American history. But he wasn't very
good at PR.
He was terrible at PR. Everyone sort of
recognized how ruthless he is. We see
movies like There Will Be Blood, which
is basically about him. In any event,
imagine if John D. Rockefeller was way
better at public relations. And instead
of calling his company Standard Oil, he
called it Safe Oil. Okay, let's just
let's just play this thought experiment.
>> Clean beautiful coal, yes. Safe oil. He
called it Safe Oil because as we know
kerosene is dangerous. Their first big
product was kerosene. And kerosene can
light your house or it can burn it down.
And in the wrong hands, it can torch a
city or you can use it to make a bomb.
So, John D
let's say should have called for the
creation of a new government agency to
regulate the safety of his product. And
they could have done rigorous testing,
licensing, common sense regulation.
There would have been a very intense
debate over safety standards.
You know, what should the proper wick
thickness be? And should we allow all
those
dangerous independent refiners, right?
And I think people would have gotten so
wrapped up in this debate over what
constituted safe oil or safe kerosene
that they would have missed what was
really going on, which is that
Rockefeller was building the richest,
most powerful monopoly of all time. In
fact, people might even have called
Rockefeller an effective altruist
because of course he was so concerned
about the safety
of his product.
>> it. Shout out to David Sacks and
writers. Great, great, great [laughter]
writers.
>> writers. Newman? Newman wrote this? No,
I wrote it.
>> Well, Emmy award for best writing in a
dramatic monologue goes to Newman. Wow,
Sacks.
>> No, that's my writing.
>> You landed it. Very good, Sacks. I
thought after the Elon Anthropic detente
where Elon said, you know, complimented
Anthropic that and David started off
with a bit of a compliment. I thought we
maybe were past this. First, it's
ridiculous to think of this as a
monopoly.
You know, we're talking about annual run
rate revenues, David, but on a GAAP
basis, they're doing about the same
revenue as OpenAI in the month of March.
Okay? So, we're way ahead of ourselves.
By the way, 5 months ago, everybody
thought OpenAI was going to run away
with this. Google's revenues are very
substantial in AI. And by the way,
Google, Amazon, etc., these companies
are producing a hundred billion dollars
of free cash flow to justify their
incremental investment. At the same
time, you have these two startups that
are still fledgling, that are still
fragile in the scheme of things,
you of all people should know we've got
the best competition in AI on the
planet, which is why we're at the
frontier and kicking the tail of
everybody else on the planet. So, I just
want to see these companies compete. I
want to see DC stay out of the way. The
last thing I want to be doing is is is,
you know, seeing people talk about this
and throwing roadblocks into the way of
the competition.
>> Um I think Anthropic is
>> Well, let me let me hold on. Let me
>> translate Brad for you. Don't with
my paper is what he's saying. He's
[laughter] got bets on these. So, Sax,
Washington, DC, don't with Brad's
paper. Sax, uh you want to get into the
uh regulation stuff right now as a segue
or Let me respond to Brad and also
translate what I'm saying satirically,
okay? Satirically. First of all, nobody
wants to see these companies compete
vigorously more than me. That was the
whole premise
of the action plan that we worked on
last year is we want to bring out the
best in everyone. This is how America's
going to win the AI race. We have five
major labs vigorously competing.
And as long as that competition is
taking place, that I think that's a good
thing. Doesn't mean we can't have
guardrails and the rest of it, but
basically competition should be our
North Star.
All of that being said, okay, what I am
pointing out and I I think it's
historically true
that people in Washington have woken up
to monopolies
on the late side, not early, right?
Because I mean, once a company has won
80% of the market, that's when they wake
up and say, "Oh, we have a monopoly
here."
And I'm not saying that they have a
monopoly yet, but if the trajectory
continues for just 18 more months,
then I think it will be in this
unpresently powerful position.
>> I mean I mean And and hold on. And I
don't think people should be distracted
from that fact
by this rhetoric around safety because
someone like Rockefeller could have used
it, too.
And I do think let me just like one one
last point on this. I do think that if
you actually look
at what a lot of the the safetyist
policies are calling for,
they're basically calling for a form of
regulatory capture. And they're calling
for things that would create a stronger
moat around this monopoly or duopoly
that's in the process of being created
and it would get in the way of
competition. So again, I think that
people
might not have such a terrible view
of all of this safety rhetoric if they
understood
that what was being created here is the
biggest monopoly in human history.
And I think we should just be a little
bit more skeptical about some of these
altruistic claims. I can't believe that
David is like you know, talking
monopolies when we haven't even left the
starting gate
of AI. I I I I think this is a uh
to me There's only two companies with
revenue.
>> thing I want is DC trying to
preemptively preemptively, which would
be like a disastrous consequence, get in
the game of picking winners and losers
at the starting line of AI. That would
be a disaster. Brad, did you just put
another soapbox on top of the soapbox
you were standing on?
>> [laughter]
>> Look, Brad. Like I said, my North Star
is competition. As long as there's
competition going on, I support it.
Hold on. Hold on. We know that
monopolists want to stop competition.
And they use regulatory capture to do
it. And furthermore, they do things like
ban their competitors from using their
product. What conceivable reason
did Anthropic have for banning OpenClaw
using its models? That is
anti-competitive. Is it not? I I I would
double click on it. I would double click
on it. I might not, you know, file, but
I would double click. Okay, listen.
Chamath, the girls are fighting. Let's
keep moving through the docket. We're
going to be here all day with these two
and one thing that you're going to need
to act on very quickly is the All-In
Summit. It's selling out fast. Don't
miss it. Speakers are top tier again.
Freeberg busy working on
some amazing speakers. Sachs will be
there. He's flying in and out every day
for 4 hours and then
>> [laughter]
>> we're
we're going to have a lot of networking
stuff going down. We're building some
networking software. So, when you come
to our events, you get to meet people.
That's what we always say. My playbook
for events, if you learn something from
the speakers every day, one or two
things, if you meet somebody new and you
eat some great food and have some fun,
you get two or three of those things,
man, even if you get one, you're going
to come back to the event. You're going
to get all three all day long.
allin.com/events Los Angeles September
13th, 14th, and 15th. Apologies to
everybody asking, but liquidity is sold
out and we've shut down the waitlist.
There's just no more room. All right,
the White House allegedly, possibly is
considering, according to reports,
an FDA for AI. That would vet You heard
that correct, folks. That would vet new
models for safety. The thing we've been
talking about not doing here. The thing
David Sachs has spent the last year on.
The White House is considering. New York
Times reported Trump is considering an
executive order to create an quote AI
working group. This group would include
tech execs and government officials who
would quote examine potential oversight
procedures
including quote a review process for new
AI models. Oy. According to the report,
the catalyst was wait for it,
Anthropic's Methuselah model, which
reportedly scared, spooked, made people
really nervous at the White House.
Quote, the White House wants to avoid
any political repercussions if a
devastating AI-enabled cyberattack were
to occur. They want to see YAA,
according to the New York Times. Kevin
Hassett, that guy, the director of the
National Economic Council confirmed the
report on Fox Business. Here's your
15-second clip.
>> We're studying possibly an executive
order to give a clear road map to
everybody about how this is going to go
and how future AIs that also potentially
create vulnerabilities should go through
a process so that you know, they're
released to the wild after they've been
proven safe just like an FDA drug.
Additionally,
friend of the pod,
Scott Bessent, had something to say.
>> had in the past month was a step change
in the power of one large language
model, but we're going to see it from
the other AI companies. What we are
determined to do is work with our AI
companies to allow them to continue
innovate, but our charge of the US
government is maintaining safety and
there there is a very important calculus
here between innovation and safety and
at the the US government, we're going to
make sure that things stay safe. There
you go. Kevin Hassett and
Bessent
slightly different positions here, Brad.
What do you think? Actually, I don't
think they're slightly different
positions, but I I I would agree that
Kevin bringing up the FDA kind of
muddied the waters. I talked to Kevin
last night after that clip ran.
You know, and I asked him. I I just
said, do you think FDA is the right
analog here? And he said, you know, I
was I was only bringing it up to say
that they we want them to show us the
models so that we can coordinate them.
Obviously, our job is to make sure that
the government is prepared, that we
harden our systems, that our
intelligence agencies are up to speed,
but he does not think and I can't find
anybody
on the right
you know, that believes that we're going
to move to an approval regime, right?
The approval regime, this idea that
you're going to have to share every
model with an FDA in Washington and
they're going to have to pre-approve the
model is a disaster. Sachs has been
effectively fighting against this
correctly over the course of the last
year. It would just it would lead to
three bad things. Number one, we do not
want to put the Washington in in the
position of picking winners and losers
when it comes to these models. We're
winning. We're on the winning horse in
America. We're out in front of the rest
of the world. There's no reason to
change horses and regimes at this point.
And we don't want to burden this with
more democracy. But at the same time,
obviously, I call these pre-AGI or AGI
models, Mistral, Spud, etc. I see a lot
of coordination going on between the
industry and government. I think we can
do an even better job of a evolving that
framework so that everybody in
government is on the same page. We need
to build more capacity in government to
quickly be able to do the cyber review
on these models. Right now, it takes too
long when the coordination does occur.
So, we need to have a finite amount of
time that they give government feedback,
etc.
But the last thing that we want is an
FDA of models sitting in Washington.
Kevin understands that. Scott Bessen
understands that. So, I expect that we
will continue down the path that we've
been on. Chamath, obviously, I think we
all agree we don't need an FDA for AI,
but
there are things that a reasonably
people would want to have guardrails
around AI. I'm sure you would agree. It
shouldn't be a total free-for-all. So,
what's your take on this? Is it just
somebody gave a bad analogy here? Or
maybe some people were weaseling their
way into the White House to try to shift
things when Sachs was back at home or
something? What what's going on here?
Give us the uh Cuz that's what I That's
what people say. They say the last
person to talk to Trump kind of has his
ear and that things can bend a certain
way.
I don't think it's that. I think that
there's a pretty profound vibe shift
with respect to tech tech oligarchs,
Silicon Valley, and particularly the AI.
That vibe shift has already happened on
Main Street.
And I think that that's starting to seep
into Washington. I think that
regulations are coming.
I think they'll be worse under a
democratic regime,
but I think that some form of oversight
is going to exist under a Republican
regime.
The question that I think is worth
asking is why.
And if you listen to everybody's tone,
it's all around the negatives of AI.
So, I think we suffer from two things.
Number one is we have horrible
messaging.
Nobody spends the time
and the money to articulate the positive
upside case
so that there's broad-based support. And
two,
the idea that there's going to be a
Sachs said earlier,
a few winners and many, many, many
potential losers,
I think is really disconcerting to
everybody.
And the response from the tech
community,
again, should be the leadership of the
tech world
coming together
and actually reinvesting in America writ
large. They're not doing that in enough
of a scale that blunts this. So, what
you're seeing is the build-up of
antibodies.
Is it avoidable? Yes.
Are we doing a good job of avoiding it?
Absolutely not. We're doing a horrible
job. I'd give the community, the tech
leaders, a D- minus
trending to an F.
The response is what we're seeing. So, I
think the question, Jason, isn't
regulation, no regulation, it's why did
we get here?
And I think we got here because the
other version, the glass half full
version, the demonstrated investment,
the broad-based uplifting of American
society hasn't happened. And if it has,
it's been very poorly communicated. And
so, the response is,
"Hey, hold on. We're going to give three
guys trillion-dollar net worths, and
we're going to allow them to control the
keys?"
That's why this is happening.
>> Exactly correct. And it's very easy,
Sachs, to imagine all the bad things
that That happen. Our minds are
constructed to do that. We're vigilant.
We look out for the tiger or, you know,
the tornado to keep ourselves safe.
Humans have a bias towards safety, and
they're going to think about, you know,
deep fakes. They're going to think about
robotics. They're going to think about
self-driving cars taking people's jobs.
They're going to think about, you know,
all the dark things that could happen.
Bio weapons, etc. And we don't have
anybody out there really talking about
all the positives that could happen.
What's your take on
the palace intrigue we all have here?
What's going on in the palace, in the
47th administration, around this debate?
Who's leading Trump down the path of
regulation and creating this AI FDA? We
know you're part of the camp that wants
to keep this train moving and not
overregulated, not have regulatory
capture. Who are the people trying to
slow this down?
Well, look, I I think there's several
things going on here. The first one is
there's a lot of fake news. This whole
idea of an FDA for AI, I don't think any
senior official supports it, just like
Brad was saying.
I spoke to Hassabis well. That's not
where his head is at. So, I don't think
anybody in the administration is saying
they want an FDA for AI. Certainly, I
don't think that's the way the president
thinks about these issues. He's the most
pro-innovation president we've ever had.
And the White House Chief of Staff,
Susie Wells, just put out a statement
last night that I think pretty much
shoots this down. So, I think there's a
big fake news component. Remember, it
was not really the White House who was
saying it was the New York Times. Mhm.
>> And really, I think actually Andrew Ross
Sorkin,
now I'm not criticizing him, but he's a
commentator, and he's the one who said
this first, and then somehow that spin
or that gloss
somehow took on a life of its own. And I
think
Silicon Valley reacted accordingly.
There's a very visceral negative
reaction here, because we know how
damaging that would be to innovation.
But, look, I think the good news is that
that was fake news. Second,
I think that there's another thing going
on, which is a straw manning of what
the Trump administration did on AI in
its first year.
And in the same way that they want to
spin this FDA for AI, they're also
trying to spin what we did as this
completely laissez-faire attitude where
there'd be no regulations whatsoever, no
guardrails. It's a way of criticizing
what we did. They're trying to portray
it as unsafe. In fact, if you look on
March 20th, White House released
a national AI regulatory framework that
I worked on, in which we put out a
four-page bulleted list of legislation
that we would support if Congress wants
to pass it. So, we have not been against
every conceivable regulation or every
conceivable law. We just believe that
there should be specific solutions to
specific problems, as opposed to a giant
power grab by Washington that would
squash innovation. So, I think that's
point number two.
Point number three is there is a
legitimate thing happening here with
let's call it Mythos or cyber. Okay, we
know that it's not just Mythos.
OpenAI now has a model that's just as
cyber capable as Mythos, and within 3 to
6 months all the major frontier labs,
and including Chinese models, will have
cyber capabilities.
In response to that, we do need there to
be a hardening of systems, and we do
need there to be a scanning of codebases
to find these vulnerabilities and patch
them before the hackers do it, because
the hackers will have these capabilities
in a matter of months. That's a
certainty, because the same capabilities
you use for cyber defense can also be
used for cyber offense. It's the same
tool set. And the open source models
will have these capabilities anyway.
>> have it to a certain extent, let's be
honest. They have 80% of it, 90% of it.
>> it's simply the case that AI will be
good at cyber, and so we do need a
response to that. Now, my view on what
should that response be should be first
of all, we should want the government
and the private sector to work
cooperatively, and I think they are. We
have a giant cybersecurity industry in
the United States whose sole job it is
to protect systems and protect against
breaches We have the best companies in
the world at doing that. We have
CrowdStrike, we have Palo Alto Networks,
we talked about that before. We have the
best defense. Right, exactly. And so
what we should be doing, I think, is
getting these tools Methos and then the
Open AI model and and others like it in
the hands of our cybersecurity industry.
And by the way, not just the public
companies like Palo Alto Networks and
CrowdStrike, all those certainly.
They're two of the most noteworthy, but
there's also some incredibly strong
startups on the way out
>> a long tail of hundreds
>> that are at the cutting edge of doing
AI-powered pen testing and all the rest
of it. We need to get these tools into
their hands as quickly as possible
because they're a force multiplier for
all the companies out there that aren't
that good at cybersecurity or maybe
they've got IT departments, they can use
these companies as vendors. So, I think
that there is a role for us to play.
>> Yeah. Do you think that the models
should
have a KYC wrapper going forward? KYC
for the audience is know your customer.
Yeah. So, what really what it would mean
is that before you can use
Methos, you have to identify yourself so
that we can try to know that you're not
a
state-sponsored actor or, you know, a
bad guy. I think that's the type of
thing that we should be thinking about.
So, first of all, I want to say that
both Anthropic and Open AI acted
responsibly here. No one was trying to
release these super powerful models. So,
in a way, all the people who are saying
that we need pre-release approvals for
models, they're trying to solve a
problem that didn't exist. Anthropic
wasn't
Yeah, they probably wasn't trying to
release this. Open AI wasn't trying to
release this. They all understood the
power and they were all acting
responsibly. They understood the
ramifications, because they would have
been sued. So, they there is a
self-policing going on here, which is
the ultimate way to do this. Yes. And
but to your point, Chamath, yeah, look,
I think that before giving your API for
a super powerful model, you should not
give that to a company or an actor you
don't know who they are. So, yeah, some
basic KYC makes sense. They should know
who they're giving these tools to. And I
guess my view on the Mythos preview and
whatever the equivalent is of what Open
AI is doing
is that we very rapidly need to get
these tools into the hands of more good
guys. You need to know who those good
guys are. You need to know who they are.
So, yeah, KYC is like a predicate for
that, right? You got to know who they
are.
>> clear, we'd all agree that if you did
have identity for those frontier models,
which they're probably doing anyway
right now, and you logged what people
were doing with them to look for
security breaches, that wouldn't
necessarily happen when you released it
to the public because of privacy issues.
Here's your Polymarket
for Trump ordering a federal review of
AI models by May 31st, 21% chance. I
think
to our partner at Polymarket, man, I I
got to get in here. I don't Do I have
inside information here being
the world's greatest moderator on this
podcast or I can Can I collect this
money, Chamath? What am I going to do
here?
>> I would not Do not Do not place a bet,
J. Cole. Don't place a bet? Don't place
a bet. But
to Chamath's point, I mean, look, I
think we're kind of work shopping this
in real time. We are. Which is good.
>> I think that for the preview period, we
should definitely have KYC. Maybe
>> logging? What about logging?
>> Well, look, once you're past the preview
period and it's in general release,
I'm not sure if the KYC matters as much
because so many people are going to have
it. But during the preview period, there
should be KYC. Let me let me just say
one thing. All the labs are already
tracking API use, okay? And anything
suspicious, because they they're they're
there are
anti-distillation efforts going on by
all the labs. There's a ton of
coordination going on with the
government. There's way more happening,
I think, in terms of our API and API
use. Um and anything suspicious is being
flagged
and being shared with the government.
So, the idea that we have no idea who's
doing it, I think, is not the case. And
in fact, in some cases, we may want to
allow people to use it so that we can
see exactly the types of things that
they are extracting. So, I would just I
would say we're already down that path,
but better coordination
may may may, in fact, be called for.
>> Yeah. And just one last point in this
whole thing is I just want to build on
my point that pre-release approvals are
solving a problem that didn't really
exist because, again, Anthropic and
OpenAI weren't trying to release these
models yet is that there is a
substantial faction of, let's say, AI
ideologues or doomers who
are basically employing the classic
never let a crisis go to waste strategy,
right? That yes, we do have this cyber
issue that is real. You know, everyone
needs to harden their systems now.
Totally. Over the next 3 to 6 months.
That is a real issue.
But that is a problem that we will solve
over the next 6 months. We have to. But
what they're trying to do is use that
issue to try and create a permanent new
infrastructure in Washington. Again, I
don't think the That's not the
administration's intention. That's not
the administration's agenda. But you saw
a lot of people
on social media, a lot of the think
tanks, and even Bernie Sanders weighed
in. And he said, "For the first time, I
like something that the Trump
administration wants to do."
>> The administration understands the 1% of
the 1% tax, and everybody understand
that this is out of control. The AI is
going to take the jobs. They're going to
take my summer home. It's going to be
terrible.
So, there are people who have this
agenda. Look, Bernie Sanders just wants
to stop the progress. I mean, he's Of
course, I do. He wants to ban data
centers. He's put out a bunch of things.
>> He He basically has bought into the
whole doomer narrative. So, look, that's
why he likes the FDA
idea is because it would put the kibosh
on innovation.
>> already. Let's give Let's have a go back
to paper and pen. It was a better
society, Sachs. Jason, what do you
think? I think there's two really
interesting things I want to build on
here. The first is your point, Chamath,
around how do we turn around the sort of
bad vibes around AI. I think we have to
have two strategies here. One is giving
what you've been working on, Brad, with
your project. We should see more people
giving. There's no reason why Nvidia,
SpaceX when they go public,
Anthropic when they go public, OpenAI if
and when they go public or if they
become stay as nonprofit, there's no
reason those folks in an IPO couldn't
give a portion of the IPO to every
American citizen. So, IPOK, IPO for
kids, they all take, you know, whatever
it is, 5%, 1%, whatever they choose, and
they put it into the Invest America
accounts. And we should see some major
giving from the people who are becoming
trillionaires, hundred billionaires,
whatever it happens to be. There's no
reason not to. But those people haven't
been doing that. We had this giving
pledge, which was a little bit of virtue
signaling, and it wasn't real. It was
just, you know, at the end of your life
you promised to give away half your
money. So, let's have something real.
Let's have something where, you know,
people say I'm going to give away 1% of
my stock over the next 20 years of my
life. Every year 1% will go into Invest
America, whatever it is. It won't cost
anybody anything. You can't spend this
money, whether it's Bezos or whatever.
Second,
and that same thing in terms of giving
back, we have not talked about how
massive this could be for health and
extending people's life and reducing
suffering. We need to work on that.
That's where contributions to basic
science could come in, and obviously
education and lowering the cost of
education. And if you look at what
Americans on the bottom have, you were
talking about the, you know, cup half
empty. There's really two or three
things they really feel anxiety about.
One of it is income, and the second is
healthcare,
and on the margins, housing and their
kids, you know, their kids' education
and the cost of those things.
We should really take a look deeply at,
and I know this is very unpopular
amongst capitalists, including myself,
we should really look at the minimum
wage and study what happened in New
Zealand, Sweden, Switzerland,
Australia when they raised it. What
actually happened when they raised it
and there was a lot of hand-wringing
about it, but when they slowly raised it
what they found was those consumers
don't save money, they spend it. They're
always behind the eight ball in terms of
their spending. We should opt in to
trying to raise the minimum wage company
by company by company, and just give
people who are at the end of the
spectrum that understanding that, "Hey,
year over year, whether it's Amazon or
Target, etc., restaurants, we're all
collectively going to add a little bit
to that minimum wage and try to lift the
bottom third of society." That's the
stuff we're not talking about. We don't
talk about it here on this podcast, we
don't talk about universal healthcare,
we don't talk about the minimum wage,
but that's what capitalists should be
talking about. And if we did that, if we
increased the minimum wage, and I'm not
a socialist, I'm a capitalist who thinks
this is good for capitalism, if we
increased the minimum wage just modestly
each year,
and we opted into doing that, and we
figured out a way to give universal
healthcare, companies wouldn't have to
deal with universal healthcare, and we
would have customers, and we're a
customer-driven economy. Like 60, 70,
80% of what happens in this country is
driven by the consumer. We need consumer
spending. It's great for companies if we
had more people being able to buy
Netflix or order on Amazon. Anyway,
that's my that's my TED Talk. Thanks for
coming. How do we get from AI to the
minimum wage? I'm still a little bit
confused about it.
>> eye. No, the black eye we have in this
country with polarization of wealth and
people scared of losing their jobs. We
we should look at why are they scared,
David? And I've talked to you privately
and you said to to privately, you can
strike this if you want, But, you said
to me privately, you wouldn't be against
necessarily figuring out a way to you
know do universal health care if there
was a way to do it. You want to see
every human have health care, yes?
Sure. I mean, the issue is not the
desirability of it, it's the cost. I
mean
>> So, you're the real entrepreneur of our
time. How would you do it? Have you
given any cycle to it?
>> I haven't studied that issue, so I don't
know. I just know that
countries
I remember what P.J. O'Rourke once said,
which is if you think health care is
expensive now, just wait until you make
it free.
Yeah. [laughter] And
uh so, you take away all the incentives
and you have a even bigger problem.
Well, what do you think minimum wage?
Yeah, go ahead. Well, let me just Can we
just get back to AI? Listen, you guys
are right about the unpopularity of AI.
We've all seen those polls, but I want
to just put up this additional poll that
came out about the salience of this
issue, which is how important do people
think it is.
And AI ranked 29 out of 39. So, although
AI is not very popular, it is certainly
not top of mind for voters. It's not in
the top 10 issues. It's not in the top
20 issues. What is top of mind for
voters? Number one, cost of living.
Number two, the economy. And we know
that AI is deflationary. It helps with
the cost of living and it's creating an
economic boom right now, okay? It's 75%
of GDP growth in Q1. By the way, that
that economic growth is not just limited
to startups in Silicon Valley. We're
seeing a construction boom. We're seeing
a blue collar boom. We're seeing 25 to
30% wage increases for uh construction
workers.
>> Exactly.
And so on down the line. So,
>> And Brad, if you if you look at that
chart, there's health care in there,
too. So, look, my point is that AI may
not be popular, but the effects of it
actually are popular if the media would
honestly report what was happening,
which is AI is creating an economic boom
right now. It couldn't be better said,
David. You know, Bernie Sanders calling
for a moratorium, shutting down all data
data centers? We'd have negative GDP
growth this year. The stock market would
be down 15 to 20%. Unemployment would be
on the rise. You know, there is a
consequence to the government
controlling through command and control
the economy. In 1929, we had 4%
unemployment. 3 years later, it was
unemployment was 23%
because government got involved in
regulating everything and shutting down,
you know, what was working. That is the
greatest threat we have here. AI is
delivering huge net benefits today in
terms of unemployment rate, in terms of
economic growth and productivity growth.
We need to tell the story. But, to
Chamath's earlier point, we also need to
deliver net benefits. Jason, thanks for
the shout-out. Yes, every American
having an investment account that
compounds with the upside of AI, we're
going to do that. Going to deliver that,
and that's going to be massive. But, I
also think ideas like, if we're going to
put a data center in Abilene, Texas,
let's make electricity in Abilene free
for the households in Abilene, Texas,
right? There are ideas that can deliver
net benefits. We got to deliver those. I
think we're Optimism will be on the
march. I think we're in the trough right
now.
>> take on minimum wage and universal
health care, Brad? How do you think
about it as a capitalist, as an
innovator, and in the face of AI, which
could have a dramatic impact on these
issues?
You know, like Zach's, I I you know, to
me, I haven't spent a ton of time
thinking about those except that as a
society, we're $38 trillion in debt. We
haven't been able to afford to deliver
those things. I generally think the
market works out those
issues better than the government
top-down trying to, you know, the
government gets more and more involved
in health care, and the only thing that
happens it gets more expensive. So,
we've all seen the charts of the most
expensive categories where we've had
inflation, education, health care, etc.
It's where the government's involved. I
actually think if you just let the
markets work, we're entering in into an
age of abundance. A lot of these
problems are going to be solved. People
are going to have a lot of AI coaches in
health care and education, etc. Let the
market work. Government stay at bay,
keep things safe. We're on a good march.
I think this
proves my point perfectly. If you talk
to any founder, they're not thinking
about housing, they're not thinking
about higher education costs, they're
not thinking about minimum wage, you
know, and they're not thinking about
healthcare all that often. Some Some do
though. There's some innovation there.
And it's because it's so regulated that
entrepreneurs and VCs are just like,
"That's Kryptonite. The government has
poisoned the well. We can't participate
in that." And that's the roadblock. And
that's where Americans are suffering.
And that's where it would be great if
founders actually put their minds to it.
And the government's got to get rid of
all that regulation and let us cook in
those specific verticals. All right, the
market is in hyperdrive. Hyperscaler
revenue has made the markets move up. We
hit on this briefly, but we didn't have
you here. Fifth best EB G cloud
computing on a tear. I referenced it
earlier, but AWS is now on a $150
billion run rate. Azure 108 billion, GCP
Google Cloud 80 billion. There's a
little bit of fun with numbers there,
Chris. Azure and Microsoft include some
of their software products in there. And
Google Cloud includes things like Google
Office or Google Suite in there.
But the growth numbers are tremendous.
AWS, which is the more pure play of the
three, 28% growth on a very big number.
Azure 39%. Google Cloud stunning
everybody with 63%
growth. It is incredible what the ARR
numbers are. Google Cloud added 10, AWS
10, Azure 9.5. So basically 30 billion
collectively. Jamin Ball, who works for
you, I think put out some data on the
Twitter.
Brad, markets at all times high all time
highs.
Mag 7 cooking.
Uber blowing out growth, Disney blowing
out growth. The consumer seems absurdly
strong based on those two bellwethers.
Tech seems extremely strong based on the
cloud computing. What's your take on the
overall market and overall economy?
Obviously, inflation up a bit, people
hand-wringing about the never-ending war
and the cost of oil. Let's just
telescope way out. You know, the level
of criticism directed to this
administration, right? Tariffs were
going to cause hyperinflation, we're
going to destroy GDP,
uh conflicts in Venezuela and Iran were
going to do the same. You know, we've
heard all of the negative stories, but
what's happening? Accelerating GDP.
A tenure that's sitting at 4.3.
Inflation totally under control. AI, AI,
AI, compute, compute, compute. We're
leading the world. It's contributing
massively, right, to GDP growth in the
country. We see the S&P only up 8% this
year, right? So, we're not in the bubble
territory here. Meta's trading at 17
times fully taxed GAAP earnings, Nvidia
at 19 times, Microsoft at 20 times,
Google at 24 times. And then the memory
stocks that everybody's excited about,
we have 25% of our portfolio in SK Hynix
five times fully taxed GAAP earnings,
Samsung six times, Micron seven times,
right? This is not the stuff that
bubbles are made of. You know, David
referenced it earlier. We started the
year Open AI and Anthropic were doing
combined about 30 billion in revenue.
Now combined, four months later, 80
billion in revenue. The the policies of
this administration on the economy are
working. They're working in in spades.
Our gap on the rest of the world in AI
is growing. And so from from my
perspective, you know, uh you know,
we've been all in on the market. I
talked about it earlier in the year.
We're heavily tilted
>> that switch to go all in on the market?
Cuz you were bearish.
Uh I'd say toward the toward the end of
last year, the market had run up a lot.
We had a lot of these questions. Listen,
entering this year, there was a huge
question hanging over the market. Would
the AI revenue show up?
If the Anthropic revenues hadn't shown
up and we didn't see this
re-acceleration out of the hyperscalers,
the market would be down 10 to 15%
because people would say there's no ROI
on all of this investment in
infrastructure. Exactly. When I saw the
numbers start showing up in December and
into January, we went from medium to
large in terms of our exposures and 80%
of our exposures or more have been in
compute, AI, memory, etc. And this is
why it's great to operate in the private
market and the public market because you
can see things in the private markets
that inform the public markets. But, the
question remains, Brad, how much better
would the economy have been doing
you know, as much credit as you're
giving to the administration if they
didn't start a $100 billion war that we
did not need to go into, according to
all reports, and if we didn't do a bunch
of tariffs that wound up being
unconstitutional by the Supreme Court,
which Trump himself put in. We would
have been further ahead. That's uh my
take on it. We would be ripping even
more if we didn't have those uh silly
diversions.
>> It's It's It's hard to imagine, okay?
Just to set up again here.
It's hard to imagine a more Goldilocks
situation for the United States of
America. We have reset the table
geopolitically. The discount rate
globally is actually coming down, not
going up, evidenced by markets at
all-time high and the bond market in
control. And then, look at the private
markets. We have multiple
trillion-dollar companies that have been
created in the private markets that are
now coming public. SpaceX coming public
is going to be a multi-trillion dollar
you know OpenAI, Anthropic, like at some
point you just have to acknowledge USA
is winning. Of course, there are always
things that we could be doing better,
but there's not a country on the world
that wouldn't trade all of its fortune
for the United States fortune today.
>> 100% in agreement. American
exceptionalism as embodied by the great
companies in America, SpaceX, Google,
etc. All the ones we've been talking
here. That is the story and I give
infinite credit to this administration
for being business-friendly. I do think
they've made two critical mistakes. I
think the tariffs were poorly executed
and I think we shouldn't have gone to
this war
and we should find a quick resolution to
it which the administration seems to be
desperately doing. Sachs, your take on
the economy.
Well, look, we have an AI boom going on
right now and I think that's thanks to
President Trump's policies. Remember,
the first week he was in office, he
rescinded the Biden policies on chips
and models. And what were those
policies? It was the approval regime
that we're talking about. Models would
have to go to Washington to get approved
if they were trained with some number of
flops and then every sale of a GPU
worldwide would have to be licensed from
Washington unless it fit into some
narrow exemptions. So, the whole
approach of the Biden administration
>> Exactly. that President Trump inherited
was everything approved in Washington.
He rescinded that. He declared that we
had to win the AI race and he unleashed
our companies to do that. Now, one other
really important thing is energy.
Remember, it was this president, going
back a decade, who said, "Drill, baby,
drill." He said, "We have to unleash
American energy. That's the basis for
the American economy. It's also the
basis for AI."
He also has said that he wanted to allow
our AI companies to become energy
companies so they could bring their own
power to these data centers so they're
not drawing off the grid. They're not
competing with consumers for
electricity. They're generating their
own power. And it's thanks to this
president that we have seen this
blue-collar construction boom right now
powering all of this infrastructure.
What would the alternative been?
We know. I mean, Bernie Sanders has said
it. Would have been ban on data centers.
So,
Yeah. Right now, we have taxes banning
data centers. It's That would be a much
a much worse choice. Chamath, I'll give
you the last word here as we wrap on the
economy generally. I think the markets
are going to keep going up for a while.
And then at some point they're going to
go down.
Okay, I wrote it down. Uh Chamath, you
said markets are up and then eventually
they're going to come down.
Those are the two things. Up and let me
put a U here and then a D here. It's got
the I think you're doing a an impression
of the taking notes emoji. Is that what
you're doing? Yes. Yeah, I just Okay,
I'll shut down.
Wow. Thank you for tuning in to All-In
where you can get your great calls and
market action advice. It's going to go
up and then down, folks. Act
accordingly. Good. Chamath, in all
seriousness, but what what what makes
you bullish, you know, let's say in the
next 6 months, 12 months catalysts and
then what do you think the headwinds are
as well? Let's take the, you know, the
short to mid-term 6 months to 2 years.
I think that in the short term
the people that
makes the new thing
needs
to get valued and needs to demonstrate
value. So, who are the people making the
new thing?
It's the Nvidias, it's the memory
makers, it's the Anthropic's, it's the
SpaceX's and uh it's the OpenAIs. But
eventually it all comes home to roost.
And
you can't just make things for a market
who then doesn't have a measurable
benefit themselves.
To be very clear and blunt, there is
literally not a scintilla of evidence
that AI has helped lift the operating
margins of the S&P 500.
There's all kinds of bluster. There's
going to be a an important fork in the
road. It's probably 2 or 3 years from
now. One path will be
OpEx shrinks
hence margins increase.
And the other path is revenues grow and
margins expand. And OpEx stays flat but
it or maybe it even goes up.
Those two things are very important
differences, because in the former
you're talking about shrinking workforce
and shrinking off backs as a percentage
of operating margin and revenue. In the
latter, you're actually growing through
it.
The answer to that question I think is
critical about how the markets will
respond.
And how society will respond. So I think
we have kind of call it 500 days
where
you just got to be net long.
But I think it's literally in the
hundreds of days from now
500.
You're going to have to have an
important reckoning moment. The people
that are paying for all these tokens
need to see it an actual benefit. Yeah,
that that's reasonable. Yeah. That's a
really interesting point. Let me connect
a couple of dots here between something
Chamath said and what Brad said, which
is
Brad said at the beginning of the year,
we went into this year with this massive
CapEx, this massive investment
infrastructure, but people weren't sure
that the ROI was going to be there in
terms of model revenue. And that was
true, and then the model revenue has
proven out. And now what Chamath is
saying is that we're going to be at
another fork in the road soon in terms
of whether there's going to be ROI
on all those tokens that are being sold
and generating the revenue for those
model companies. And I agree with you
that that is not proven out yet, but I'm
optimistic that it is going to be proven
out and otherwise these you wouldn't be
seeing Look, I enterprises continue to
to buy. Hold on, let me just finish my
point.
You wouldn't be seeing enterprise
continue their month-over-month spend
on coding tokens if they didn't feel
like the ROI was going to be there. But
you make a good point, which is what is
the impact on the economy going to be
when all of this new stuff where this
bespoke software that's being created
through again all these coding tokens
that are being bought is going to power
a wave of productivity like I think
we've never seen before. So I think what
you're seeing is the ROI is getting is
sort of trickling down from
infrastructure to model to application
to end user. And I think it's going to
create an economic boom. I got I got it.
I'm with you, Sachs. It's This is déjà
vu all over again. We watched this
happen with the PC revolution, the
internet revolution, cloud revolution,
mobile revolution. We had all this
hand-wringing. Will this ever pay off?
Should I build an app? Should I build a
website? Should I not? Should I move to
the cloud? Should I keep it on prem? All
of these questions over and over and
over again. And then they went from
question marks to exclamation points. I
can tell you inside of my firm, we have
started We were using agents then we
started building code. And I've got
three people on the team who are making
all the interfaces and products that a
22-person
investment firm should not be making
internally. They should be using SaaS
software. And they are shipping product
day in and day out. The ROI is fait
accompli, Brad. It is fait accompli. I
think this has been decided. I think
it's been decided. It has not been
decided at all. It has not been decided
at all. You have 80/90. You're working
with the big enterprises. I invest in
100 startups a year. I work with the
small ones. It is fait accompli with
startups. They are building software.
They're shipping. They are getting
massive value from these tokens. And
they're getting so much value that they
don't have to add, you know, but half
the number of employees that they would
with the same amount of capital. They're
getting further with less money. It is
working in startup land. I don't know
what's happening at 80/90. You would
have a better picture, obviously, of the
enterprise. Tell us what you see there.
I mean, our business is doing well, but
what I'm trying to get across to you
guys is that
you can't will
profits to go up.
Okay? So, ultimately what happens is I'm
just going to take a company randomly.
Anheuser-Busch.
They have to eventually sell more beer.
Okay? Take Nike.
They ultimately have to sell more shoes.
Take
a medical devices company. They have to
sell more artificial hips and knees.
So, the The I'm trying to get across is
right now there's an enormous amount of
very constructive and creative
experimentation.
But I think it's what is also true is a
lot of that
has not yet proven value. I don't think
that means it's going to stop. All I'm
just trying to say is
until a company can trace very directly
I spent X and I made Y where Y is now
greater than X and it's lifted my
margins
that is the thing that causes the
flywheel to spin faster.
And right now we've started the first
part of that equation. We've spent the
X.
And we have not seen the Y.
You would see it in global GDP. You
haven't. You would see it in global
productivity. You haven't. You would see
it in the global profit margins of the
S&P 500. We haven't. It doesn't mean
it's not coming. Brad, you want to you
want to pick up on this because I yeah,
I'm definitely taking the other side of
it cuz I'm seeing with a lot of these
companies massive lowering of costs.
Their ads are getting more effective. At
the same time they've stopped hiring.
They're not adding positions in a lot of
cases. And things like just pick the
Nike example
a lot of the photo shoots
they used to do for their app, excuse
me. A lot of the imagery they used to
make now they're able to make more of it
without having to hire photographers and
do that stuff. I know this example cuz
we have a startup that does this
specifically for brands like Nike.
They've seen a massive drop. We have one
that helped DoorDash with their food
pictures. All those pictures used to
have to be taken by photographers. Now
it's all done by AI. Massive reduction
in cost and they're using ads and ad
creative now at that is, you know, you
know, double-digit percentage more
effective while costing half as much. So
I definitely think we're seeing it on
the earnings. But is is that true? Are
you seeing it in the earnings of these
companies yet? Yeah, so so two data
points. Number one, we just saw Azure
grow 39% in the quarter. We saw Google
Cloud grow 63% in the quarter. Headcount
growth for those companies the last 3
years mag 5 combined is about 3%. So
their operating margins are all
expanding. If you look at the S&P 500
writ large in Q1 of 24 operating margins
were about 11.8%
that was up from 11% in 23. This year
they're 13%. So we've had a 200 basis
point improvement in the operating
margins of the S&P 500 which is massive.
Do you think that's AI across those
businesses?
>> I think that that's the question where
where it could dovetail with what you're
saying. It's dollars to donuts it's not
AI. Yeah, so I So but any amount of
money is not AI. I bet you it's the same
financial engineering that got these
earnings to rise in the last decade.
Yeah, so I I I think that's the
question. Are Is this margin expansion
durable? The forecast the consensus
forecast and estimate is that margins
are going to continue to expand over the
course of the next 2 years. You and I
both know back in 22 23 we went from the
age of excess to the age of fitness,
right? A lot of these companies were
able to shed people, you know, with the
excuse of AI just because they had
become you know,
too excessive during the period of
COVID. So I I think it's a legitimate
question whether or not that's all from
AI, but I will tell you anecdotally it
maps for me. I'm hearing like Jason and
David a lot of these companies that are
you know, really growing their top lines
at an accelerating rate without
expanding head count nearly at the same
pace. Okay. Sacks, I'll give you the
final word while we're at it. Brad was
talking about how we got all these
operating efficiency improvements. The
unemployment rate stayed at historic
lows during that time. I mean the
economists consider full employment to
be 4 to 5%. And we've stayed at you
know, the low low 4% 4.2% roughly during
this time. So you're able to get these
efficiency improvements while
unemployment is still extremely low.
Moreover, there was just a big article
saying that the unemployment rate for
young college graduates has dropped. So,
you know, there was this whole narrative
recently that recent college graduates
were going to have the hardest time
finding jobs because you know, there's
going to be no no work left for
entry-level jobs because of AI. And in
fact, it has gotten easier for recent
college graduates to find work recently.
Maybe that's because they're AI natives.
Maybe that's because they know how to
use AI better.
So, in any event, I mean, we're just not
seeing any evidence yet of these
theoretical downsides of AI around job
loss and unemployment. And we are
starting to see big productivity gains.
Yeah. I mean, this is going to be a
circular discussion, but yeah, there's a
lot of conflicting evidence. The last
piece of conflicting evidence,
obviously, is the labor participation
rate because if you are not even opting
into participate, then you
you know, don't get counted as
unemployed. And that's been, I think, a
big challenge. 61.9% in March labor
participation rate.
Back in before COVID, we were at 63.3.
Yeah, and college graduates are hearing
different stories. Certain degrees
getting jobs, other ones not getting
jobs.
It's too early to tell. Uh I think is
probably what we all agree in. And it's
a it's a mixed bag. No, no, I don't
agree with that. No. Which Look,
whenever whenever I have data to refute
one of your narratives, you always say
it's too soon to tell.
No, no, no. What I Headline, Wall Street
Journal. Nick, put it on the screen.
College graduates are finally catching a
break in this job market. Yeah. J. Kyle,
you should be happy about this.
>> I know. I'm Listen, I'm happy anybody
gets a job. But what you do is then you
say we don't trust the numbers and we
should get rid of the Fed and we should
get rid of the numbers. I also said get
rid of the Fed. No, that was Schmo I was
saying But you you told us Schmo to get
rid of the Fed cuz we don't like the
numbers. Listen, it's all great. Welcome
to the debate club. What did I say? You
said abolish the Fed.
Abolish the Fed.
What is the Fed here for? All right,
listen. Enough. We're getting into Trump
Derangement Syndrome or Trump Ben the
Knee Syndrome. It's the end of the show.
We had a great show, everybody. We had
some laughs. We all learned. We
workshopped some stuff. Let's leave it
where it is. Great job, President Trump.
>> to I want to congratulate Oh, here we
go.
I want to congratulate all of our
innovators, and I want to congratulate
Elon and um Dario De Rockefeller on
their recent deal. Oh, SHOTS [laughter]
FIRED. THIS IS GETTING STRAIGHT. Come on
the program anytime, Dario. Hey, you
know Dario well, Brad. Get him on the
program. Next week, I want him on the
program. Have him come on. I mean, I I
I'm going to ask Ask him for me.
I
um Will you ask him for me?
Well, I I sure I'll ask him. And you you
you know, the the the the fact of the
matter is
I thank our lucky stars that we have
Elon, that we have Anthropic, that we
have OpenAI, that we have Google, that
we have Amazon all innovating in this
country. And you know, I know we like to
you know, kind of poke poke fun on the
edges of these things, but the fact of
the matter is
you know, I see them all
showing up, sharing their models,
driving as hard as they can to innovate.
We have the best competitive framework
in the country. David's right, it's been
transformed over the course of the last
14 months. We need to stay the course.
We're on the winning horse. We just had
the Derby last week.
>> There it is. On the winning horse. Stay
on the horse. America for the win.
America for the win. There it is,
Senator Brad Gerstner. I think if you're
going to run, you got to get rid of the
red glasses. We got to get rid of the
corduroy [laughter] shorts in there. But
yeah, I think you got a you got a
serious shot, Senator. Senator Gerstner.
>> I like I like secretary better.
Secretary. Secretary. Uh Who's Yeah,
Secretary of the Treasury, Brad
Gerstner. Secretary of Secretary of
State, David Sacks. Secretary of
Cashmere and Wine, Chamath Palihapitiya.
How are you doing with your There's so
much fake news out there because I mean,
look, I totally agree with everything
Brad said. Look, I poke fun at at some
of these companies for some of the
things they do, but I am happy that they
are American companies and that they're
innovating here.
>> Congratulations on your Metaverse deal.
Absolutely. Yes. And look, there's so
much fake news out there. I mean, we
just covered on this podcast how
beneficial some of these economic trends
are. You never get it from the media.
And they are trying to derail us from
from, you know, the the policies that
have been so successful. Yes, but they
did some great inspiring coverage of
micro looting, so get your micro looting
on.
>> [laughter]
>> Congratulations New York Times. We'll
see you next time everybody. Bye-bye.
Love you boys. Love you best.
>> [music]
>> Let your winners ride.
Rain Man David Sacks.
And [music] I said, we open sourced it
to the fans and they've just gone crazy
with it. Love you Wes. I'm Queen of
Quinoa.
>> [music]
>> Let the winners ride.
Besties are back.
>> [music]
>> That is my dog taking a in your
driveway, Sacks. Wait a minute.
Oh man. My hot Natasha will meet me at
the Russian Tea Room. We [music] should
all just get a room and just have a one
big huge orgy cuz they're all just
useless. It's like this like sexual
tension that they just need to release
somehow.
>> [music]
>> What? You're a big baby. Wipe your
little tear face. What? What?
>> [laughter]
>> We need to get merch.
>> Besties are back.
I'm going all in.
>> [music]
>> I'm going [music] all in.